Chris Sexton

gsexton@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/CJSexton 1-425-502-0574

Senior Information Technology and Data Solutions Specialist with 15 years of experience leading organizations through complex data strategies and technological growth. Insatiably curious thought leader, resolving client business problems and orchestrating process improvements. Passionately lead data analytics, data warehousing and reporting solutions to promote client business growth and technology edge. Manage cross-functional projects and Data Engineering groups, turn around dysfunctional teams and guide employee development. Calm influence, make sense from chaos and bridge the gap between business and technology.

Big Data Evangelism Customer Advocacy

Leadership and Vision Project and Program Management

Management Excellence Customer Experience Management (CEM)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Conduent Legal and Compliance Solutions, Redmond, WA Director of Analytics, Development

Jun 2016 - Present

Research and Development in advanced analytics products and services for Conduent Legal and Compliance Solutions.

Lead a global team of data scientists and data engineers to develop machine learning solutions for corporate legal customers. Create innovative product solutions for compliance, eDiscovery, content moderation and contract analysis using big data text analysis.

- Collaborate with pre-sales, operations, development and R&D teams to create full life cycle, implementable ML models, delivered in product or as a service.
- Successfully design and build software prototypes to win multiple sales opportunities.
- Drive operational efficiency in the development process, including hiring (on shore and off shore), process improvements and best practice.
- Provide thought leadership both internally and externally through demos, client engagements and speaking engagements.

Xerox, Redmond, WA

Jan 2016 – Jun 2016

Director Data Science and Engineering, Analytics Resource Center

Developed the operational core of a new Xerox center of excellence providing data science expertise to the services organization.

• Enabled Xerox businesses to improve competitiveness through product development and integration of advanced analytics.

Wireless Data Services (WDS), a Xerox Company, Kirkland WA Vice President, Information Systems

Aug 2011 – Jan 2016

Influenced, planned and lead high growth organizational strategies and solutions for clients, based on insightful data research and algorithmic findings. Related technical world of data analytics to C-Level and stakeholder audiences, inspiring business vision and direction.

- Contributed consultative Data Analytics expertise, leading to the winning of major clients in Customer Journey Insight and Contact Center reporting, with revenue valued at more than \$3m annually.
- Drove design and formulation of the Data Analytics Center of Excellence, leading recruitment and on boarding of data scientists, engineers and product owners to provide consulting and product development in Customer Experience Management

- Influenced leadership strategy, as Trusted Advisor on the Senior Management team, to successfully grow and position WDS to the point of planned sale and subsequent successful acquisition by Xerox.
- Composed and drove \$10m budget for business centric Information Technology strategy, producing improvements to WDS and customers' infrastructure, productivity tools, connectivity and information systems.
- Delivered multiple customer and service improvement projects, including unified communications, policy changes, risk management and technology refreshes, resulting in more than \$500k savings annually
- Introduced iterative approach to project management based on delivering value based outcomes, providing visibility and accountability on the cost and delivery of Information Systems resulting in the completion of a stalled \$1m storage and virtualization overhaul.

Wireless Data Services, Poole, UK / Kirkland, WA

Nov 2006- Aug 2011

Director, Global Information Systems

Produced and executed the Information and Data strategy to deliver customer reporting and operational insight.

- Turned around operational reporting department, delivering improved response times and increased capacity to customers and business. Improved reporting accuracy and acceptance rate from 74% to 100%.
- Negotiated with the Department of Labor to reduce a \$3.3m fee to \$300k through the analysis and presentation of Call Center data metrics.
- Collaborated closely with Leadership and customers to create analytic and reporting solutions on pre- and post-sales engagements, resulting in winning the services implementations of several Tier One customers in the Wireless industry.
- Built and managed cross functional global team of 12 developers, database administrators and operational staff responsible for the maintenance, security and delivery of corporate data.

Wireless Data Services, Poole, UK Global Program Manager

Jan 2006- Nov 2006

Wireless Data Services, Poole, UK Web Services and Database Manager Dec 2000- Jan 2006

Global Crossing, Basingstoke, UK **UK and European Database Manager**

Jun 1997- Dec 2000

EDUCATION:

Bournemouth University, UK **BSc Business Information Technology** UC Berkeley, CA **Masters Information and Data Science**, in progress

TECHNICAL SKILLS: SQL, PLSQL, Oracle, SQLServer, PostgreSQL, MadLib, Greenplum, R, Python, Linux/Unix/SunOS, Scripting, AWS, MS Office, Confluence, SharePoint, Agile, Waterfall, SDLC, Shiny, Azure, Databricks, BI tools, Business Objects, Qlik